<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swift on Mahi Garg</title>
    <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/tags/swift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swift on Mahi Garg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mahigarg.github.io/tags/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Count with where clause (count(where:)) in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/count-with-where-clause-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/count-with-where-clause-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In Swift, the count(where:) method is a powerful tool for filtering and counting elements in a collection that meet specific criteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initializer in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/initializer-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/initializer-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In Swift, initializers are fundamental building blocks that allow you to create instances of classes, structures, and enumerations by setting up their initial state.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thread Safety in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/thread-safety-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/thread-safety-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Thread safety refers to a programming concept where data or resources are accessed and modified in a way that ensures correct behavior and prevents conflicts when multiple threads (concurrent execution units) are working with the same data simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unowned vs Optional Unowned References in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/unowned-vs-optional-unowned-references-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/unowned-vs-optional-unowned-references-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Memory management is a critical consideration in Swift development, and managing references is a key aspect of this. Two reference types that come into play are unowned and optional unowned references.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weak vs Unowned References in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/weak-vs-unowned-references-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/weak-vs-unowned-references-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Memory management is a vital consideration when developing applications, and Swift provides developers with different reference types to manage memory effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong vs Weak vs Unowned References in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/strong-vs-weak-vs-unowned-references-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/strong-vs-weak-vs-unowned-references-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In the world of Swift programming, memory management is a critical aspect that developers need to consider to create efficient and reliable apps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conditional Expressions in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/conditional-expressions-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/conditional-expressions-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Conditional expressions lie at the heart of programming, allowing developers to make decisions and control the flow of their code. In Swift, these expressions provide the foundation for branching logic and executing different paths based on conditions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retain Cycle in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/retain-cycle-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/retain-cycle-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift&amp;rsquo;s automatic reference counting (ARC) system does a great job of managing memory, there&amp;rsquo;s a phenomenon called retain cycle that can sneakily lead to memory leaks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>@objc in swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/objc-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/objc-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>The @objc attribute in Swift facilitates seamless interaction between Swift and Objective-C codebases by exposing Swift declarations to the Objective-C runtime.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>class vs struct: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/classes-vs-struct-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/classes-vs-struct-swift/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of Swift programming, the choice between using classes or structs can significantly impact your code&amp;rsquo;s design, efficiency, and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nested Methods in swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/nested-methods-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/nested-methods-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Nested methods in Swift allow you to define a function within the body of another function. This inner function is only accessible within the enclosing function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/super-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/super-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In the dynamic world of Swift programming, the super keyword serves as a bridge connecting the past and present—enabling seamless inheritance and collaboration between parent and child classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift Enum in detail</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/swift-enum-in-detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/swift-enum-in-detail/</guid>
      <description>Enumerations, commonly known as enums, are a versatile feature in Swift that allow you to define a group of related values in a structured manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/self-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/self-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of Swift programming, mastering the self keyword is essential for crafting clean and efficient code. This small but mighty keyword plays a significant role in object-oriented design, allowing developers to access and manipulate instance-specific properties and methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Error Handling with do-catch in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/error-handling-with-do-catch-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/error-handling-with-do-catch-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Error handling is a crucial aspect of writing robust and reliable software applications. In Swift, the do-catch construct provides a powerful mechanism for handling errors and gracefully recovering from unexpected situations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Operator (as vs as? vs as!) in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/as-operator-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/as-operator-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Type casting is a fundamental concept in Swift that allows you to work with instances of different types in a flexible and safe manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Operator (is vs is? vs is!) in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/is-operator-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/is-operator-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Type checking is a crucial concept in Swift that allows you to determine the type of an instance or value at runtime.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Try Statement (Try vs Try? vs Try!) in SWift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/try-statement-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/try-statement-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Error handling is an integral part of any programming language, and Swift provides a versatile set of tools to handle errors effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type Casting (as Operator) in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/type-casting-as-operator-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/type-casting-as-operator-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Type casting is a powerful feature in Swift that allows you to work with instances of different types in a flexible and safe manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type Checking (is Operator) in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/type-checking-is-operator-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/type-checking-is-operator-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Type checking is a fundamental concept in programming languages, including Swift. It enables you to determine the type of a value or an instance at runtime, facilitating dynamic behavior and robust code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If let vs Guard let in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/if-let-vs-guard-let-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/if-let-vs-guard-let-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Working with optionals is a common scenario in Swift, allowing us to handle situations where a value might be present or absent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Property in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/lazy-property-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/lazy-property-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift&amp;rsquo;s lazy properties are a remarkable feature that allows developers to defer the initialization of a property until it is first accessed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computed Property in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/computed-property-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/computed-property-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In Swift, computed properties are a powerful and elegant feature that allows developers to define custom accessors for their properties. Unlike stored properties, computed properties do not store a value directly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>guard let in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/guard-let-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/guard-let-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of Swift programming, handling optionals with precision is of paramount importance to ensure code safety and maintainability. One of the most elegant constructs for handling optionals is the guard let statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Default Statement in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/default-statement-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/default-statement-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>When working with switch statements in Swift, we often encounter situations where we need to handle known cases explicitly. However, there are times when we also want to handle unknown or unexpected cases gracefully.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>if let in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/if-let-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/if-let-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift is known for its safety and strong typing, and one of its most powerful features is its handling of optionals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continue Statement in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/continue-statement-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/continue-statement-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Loop control is a fundamental aspect of programming, allowing developers to iterate over collections and execute specific tasks. However, in real-world scenarios, not every iteration requires the same action.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift Functions: Single and Multiple Value Returns</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/swift-functions-single-and-multiple-value-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/swift-functions-single-and-multiple-value-returns/</guid>
      <description>In Swift, functions are the building blocks of code that encapsulate logic and perform specific tasks. They can return values to the caller, either as a single value or as multiple values using tuples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switch Statement in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/switch-statement-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/switch-statement-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift&amp;rsquo;s powerful switch statement is a versatile control flow construct that enables developers to handle complex conditions and pattern matching with ease.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closures: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/closures-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/closures-swift/</guid>
      <description>Closures are a powerful feature of the Swift programming language that allows you to write code that can be passed around and executed at a later time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Break Statement in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/break-statement-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/break-statement-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Control flow is an essential aspect of any programming language, and Swift is no exception. Swift provides a powerful and flexible control flow mechanism that allows developers to direct the flow of their code execution based on certain conditions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ternary Conditional Operator in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/ternary-conditional-operator-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/ternary-conditional-operator-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift&amp;rsquo;s Ternary Conditional Operator is a concise and powerful tool that allows developers to write compact conditional expressions. It provides a more concise alternative to traditional if-else statements, making code more readable and expressive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enums in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/enums-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/enums-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to writing clean, maintainable, and bug-free code, Swift provides a powerful feature called enums or enumerations. Enums are a fundamental data type that allows developers to define a set of related values in a type-safe manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inout in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/inout-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/inout-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift, being a modern and versatile programming language, offers various features to enhance code functionality and readability. One such powerful feature is the inout parameter, which allows two-way communication between a function and its caller.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structs in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/structs-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/structs-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to designing data structures in Swift, one of the fundamental building blocks you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter is the struct. A struct, short for structure, is a versatile and lightweight data type that allows you to encapsulate related properties and behaviors together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuple in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/tuple-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/tuple-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In Swift, tuples are lightweight data structures that provide a simple and elegant way to group multiple values together. They offer great versatility and are widely used in various scenarios to pass around related pieces of data effortlessly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classes in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/classes-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/classes-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In the world of Swift, classes form the cornerstone of object-oriented programming (OOP). They provide a powerful mechanism to create blueprints for objects, allowing you to encapsulate data and behaviors together in a structured manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dictionary: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/dictionary-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/dictionary-swift/</guid>
      <description>Dictionaries in Swift provide a key-value pair mechanism for efficient data storage and retrieval. They are implemented using hash tables, allowing fast access and modification of values based on keys.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protocols in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/protocols-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/protocols-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In Swift, protocols are a powerful tool that empowers developers to create flexible, reusable, and scalable code. They play a pivotal role in achieving abstraction and enabling polymorphism, essential principles of object-oriented programming (OOP).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extensions in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/extensions-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/extensions-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Extensions in Swift allow developers to add new functionality to existing classes and protocols without modifying their original implementation. For classes, extensions can include new methods, computed properties, and initializers, promoting code modularity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generics in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/generics-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/generics-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Generics allow us to write functions, structures, and classes that can work with different types while maintaining type safety. Rather than specifying concrete types, we use placeholders (type parameters) that get substituted with actual types when the code is used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variable Types in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/variable-types-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/variable-types-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift is a powerful and versatile programming language that allows developers to create robust and efficient applications across various platforms. One of the fundamental aspects of Swift is its strong type system, which ensures safety and reliability in code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>let vs var: Mutability in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/let-vs-var-mutability-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/let-vs-var-mutability-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift is a powerful and modern programming language that allows developers to build robust and efficient applications for various platforms. One of the key features of Swift is its support for both immutable constants and mutable variables through the use of let and var declarations, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optional Type in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/optional-type-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/optional-type-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift is a robust and modern programming language that prioritizes safety and reliability. One of the key features that contribute to Swift&amp;rsquo;s safety is its handling of optional types.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do While (Repeat While) Loop in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/do-while-repeat-while-loop-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/do-while-repeat-while-loop-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift is a powerful and expressive programming language that offers a variety of loop structures to handle repetitive tasks efficiently. Among these, the do-while loop stands out as a loop that ensures the code inside the loop executes at least once, regardless of the loop&amp;rsquo;s condition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>While Loop in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/while-loop-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/while-loop-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In any programming language, loops are essential for performing repetitive tasks efficiently. Swift offers a variety of loop structures, and one of the most versatile ones is the while loop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For loop with where clause: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/for-loop-with-where-clause-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/for-loop-with-where-clause-swift/</guid>
      <description>For loop is an inevitable part of any programming language. It iterates over every element of the collection type data including array, set, and dictionary, and does the operation as per the code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Round up to n Decimal Digit: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/round-up-to-n-decimal-digit-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/round-up-to-n-decimal-digit-swift/</guid>
      <description>We sometimes in our calculation get results with more than 4 decimal digits or even more. But as a developer, we can’t use the same to display to users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/set-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/set-swift/</guid>
      <description>A set is an unordered collection of unique elements, meaning it does not allow duplicates. Swift&amp;rsquo;s Set data type ensures that each element occurs only once in the collection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Map Operator: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/map-operator-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/map-operator-swift/</guid>
      <description>The collection is something which is used by almost everyone. It makes our life easy. Array, Set, and Dictionary are the best examples of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$0, $1 … $n in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/0-1-n-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/0-1-n-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>In order to use any parameter in a closure or a higher-order function, we need to name the parameter inside the closure or higher-order function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Named and Unnamed Parameters: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/named-and-unnamed-parameters-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/named-and-unnamed-parameters-swift/</guid>
      <description>Functions are something that every developer uses daily. A function can of with or without parameters. Swift has multiple ways of passing the parameters to a function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filter Operator: Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/filter-operator-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/filter-operator-swift/</guid>
      <description>The collection is something which is used by almost everyone. It makes our life easy. Array, Set, and Dictionary are the best examples of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enumerated in Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/enumerated-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/enumerated-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Enumerated is used to iterate over a collection along with the position access. It returns a sequence of Pairs where the first element in the Pair is the index and the second element is the element itself of the collection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labeled Statement : Swift</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/labeled-statement-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/labeled-statement-swift/</guid>
      <description>Swift has a few inbuilt features which make our life super easy. Labeled statements are one of them. It allows us to name a statement and later within the scope, that particular statement can be referenced using the label provided.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
