<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SwiftUI on Mahi Garg</title>
    <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/tags/swiftui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SwiftUI on Mahi Garg</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mahigarg.github.io/tags/swiftui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fidget Loader : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/fidget-loader-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/fidget-loader-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Fidget Loader is a dynamic and visually engaging iOS component built using SwiftUI, designed to enhance user experience by providing elegant loading animations within any iOS application. This component serves as an intuitive and customizable loading indicator, seamlessly integrating into various app interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Loader : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/lazy-loader-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/lazy-loader-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Lazy Loader is a dynamic and visually engaging iOS component built using SwiftUI, designed to enhance user experience by providing elegant loading animations within any iOS application. This component serves as an intuitive and customizable loading indicator, seamlessly integrating into various app interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arc Progress Loader : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/arc-progress-loader-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/arc-progress-loader-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Arc Progress Loader is a dynamic and visually engaging iOS component built using SwiftUI, designed to enhance user experience by providing elegant loading animations within any iOS application. This component serves as an intuitive and customizable loading indicator, seamlessly integrating into various app interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Sided Fidget Loader: SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/four-sided-fidget-loader-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/four-sided-fidget-loader-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Four Sided Fidget Loader is a dynamic and visually engaging iOS component built using SwiftUI, designed to enhance user experience by providing elegant loading animations within any iOS application. This component serves as an intuitive and customizable loading indicator, seamlessly integrating into various app interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ripple Loader : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/ripple-loader-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/ripple-loader-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ripple Loader is a dynamic and visually engaging iOS component built using SwiftUI, designed to enhance user experience by providing elegant loading animations within any iOS application. This component serves as an intuitive and customizable loading indicator, seamlessly integrating into various app interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ring and Circle Loader : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/ring-and-circle-loader-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/ring-and-circle-loader-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ring and Circle Loader is a dynamic and visually engaging iOS component built using SwiftUI, designed to enhance user experience by providing elegant loading animations within any iOS application. This component serves as an intuitive and customizable loading indicator, seamlessly integrating into various app interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotating Circular Sticks Loader : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/rotating-circular-sticks-loader-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/rotating-circular-sticks-loader-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Rotating Circular Sticks Loader is a dynamic and visually engaging iOS component built using SwiftUI, designed to enhance user experience by providing elegant loading animations within any iOS application. This component serves as an intuitive and customizable loading indicator, seamlessly integrating into various app interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotating Square Loader : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/rotating-square-loader-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/rotating-square-loader-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Rotating Square Loader is a dynamic and visually engaging iOS component built using SwiftUI, designed to enhance user experience by providing elegant loading animations within any iOS application. This component serves as an intuitive and customizable loading indicator, seamlessly integrating into various app interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoreData in SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/coredata-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/coredata-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Merge data management seamlessly with UI. Model, persist, and update app data effortlessly using declarative syntax. Fetch, sort, and filter data effortlessly, ensuring a responsive and engaging user experience. Simplify synchronization between data and UI layers for efficient, scalable app development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carousel View : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/carousel-view-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/carousel-view-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A carousel view is a user interface component commonly used in mobile and web applications to display a collection of items in a horizontally scrolling manner. It allows users to swipe or navigate through a set of images, cards, or other content. The carousel view typically presents a subset of items at a time, with the ability to cycle through the remaining items. It is an engaging and intuitive way to showcase multiple pieces of content within a limited space, providing an interactive and visually appealing user experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram Post : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/instagram-post-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/instagram-post-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coding an Instagram post in SwiftUI is an engaging project. You can use various components like images, text, and buttons to design a post layout. With SwiftUI&amp;rsquo;s simple syntax and powerful features, you can easily arrange the content and customize the post&amp;rsquo;s appearance. Adding interactive features like like and comment buttons makes the post come alive. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun way to learn SwiftUI and create your own unique Instagram-style posts, perfect for displaying your creativity or sharing with friends on social media.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagarm Logo : SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/instagram-logo-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/instagram-logo-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating the Instagram logo in SwiftUI is an exciting task. Using basic shapes like circles, squares, and colors, you can piece together the iconic camera symbol and colorful gradient background. With SwiftUI&amp;rsquo;s user-friendly syntax and pre-built shape modifiers, you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy a smooth coding experience. By combining shapes and arranging them creatively, you can replicate the recognizable Instagram logo, ready to be used in your own SwiftUI projects or to explore your coding creativity. Have fun and unleash your artistic side while coding this popular logo!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List: SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/list-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/gists/list-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In SwiftUI, the &lt;code&gt;List&lt;/code&gt; is a powerful tool for creating neat and organized scrolling lists in apps. Imagine it as a virtual scrollable sheet of paper where you can display various items, like names, messages, or to-do tasks. It automatically adjusts its content, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about updating the list when things change. Whether you want to showcase a bunch of contacts or a menu with different options, &lt;code&gt;List&lt;/code&gt; makes it simple and user-friendly. Users can smoothly scroll through the content, making it easy for them to find and interact with the information you present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NavigationView in SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/navigationview-in-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/navigationview-in-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Navigation involves moving between different screens or views within an app. SwiftUI provides a navigation view hierarchy that allows users to navigate between different views seamlessly. The NavigationView is the container view that manages the navigation stack and provides a NavigationBar at the top to facilitate navigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>@State: SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/state-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mahigarg.github.io/blogs/state-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In SwiftUI, a powerful framework for building user interfaces, managing and updating the state of our views is essential for creating dynamic and interactive user experiences. One key tool SwiftUI provides for this purpose is the @State property wrapper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
